NATHAN MCKINNEY

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathanmckinney01 Email: nmckinney1@protonmail.com

Github: https://github.com/NMcKinney237/Portfolio Mobile: (847) 421-2893

SUMMARY

Data analyst and programmer with 4 years of demonstrated experience in leveraging intelligence and digital tools to mine and drive global market insights for non-profits and S&P 500 manufacturers. I chart the paths that others will follow.

SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

Expertise and Strengths

Market Intelligence and Database Analytics | Predictive Analytics | Data Wrangling | Data Visualization and Dashboards Collaborative | Efficiency-Oriented | Inclusive | Researcher | A Developer of Others

Software Knowledge (Proficiency- Scaled from Beginner to Proficient)

Microsoft Excel and Powerpoint (expert) | Python / Pandas / SciKit Learn (proficient) | Tableau (proficient) | SQL (begin.) | AWS (begin.) | Spark (begin.)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly 8/2021 – Current

Python / Data Science Bootcamp

Chicago, IL

- 500+ hour machine learning Bootcamp, utilizing Python, SQL, and Databricks/Py-Spark to perform statistical modeling and produce deliverables requiring natural language processing, recommender systems, and neural networks
- **Projects:** Regression model predicting price of house given list of features, classification model predicting Alzheimer's off of image data, and a classification model for identifying sentiment in social media posts

One Collective 9/2020 – 7/2021 Field Staff Elgin, IL

- Presented at over 80 meetings with prospective donors, and raised \$60,000 in recurring annual funding for the operations of a new entrepreneurial training center in Oman, as well as \$30,000 in seed money for its launch
- Utilized SCRUM methodologies in project development and external research activities for the team involved in the venture, and designed and evaluated social media ad campaign effectiveness for the new launch

CF Industries 6/2019 – 9/2020 Sales Analyst Chicago, IL

- Performed primary data analysis on 19 million tons of annual sales across 3 shipping modes and 8 products, evaluating manufacturing and sales team performance against regional and global sales KPI's
- Utilized Excel and Python programming to (i) craft analytical packages and dashboards for sales managers and product leads on request; (ii) data mine insights on customer, shipping, storage, and pricing trends
- Lone Tableau user for Market Research team; delivered geospatial maps and data discovery for the sales department for use in (i) board presentations; (ii) senior-level analysis on global project developments and asset investment opportunities

CF Industries 4/2017 – 5/2019 Market Research Specialist Chicago, IL

- Managed supply-side economic databases and data lead on quantitative projects involving international trade, regional production costs, price movements, and the operational capabilities of nitrogen producers in a \$115 billion market
- Prototyped Excel/Python applications automating unstructured data collection and reporting processes, and was responsible for the cut of an estimated 118 man-hours annually in 2018
- Data lead on a package utilized by CF Industries during the EU Commission's anti-dumping inquiry on U.S., Russia, and Trinidad UAN exports, highlighting the impact of rising input costs and EU production mix strategies on EU imports
- Primary authorship of (i) exec-level memorandums and in-depth due diligence on market positioning and competitor movements; (ii) trade reports detailing customs data, international trade flows, and growth trends

EDUCATION